Hello and welcome to this session on
what's new in page scripting.
So,
hopefully you know that we launched page
scripting tool some releases ago,
probably actually some years ago. And we
launched it in in preview back then.
And the page scripting tool allows
customers and consultants to record and
replay user actions directly in the web
client. For example, as part of user
acceptance tests.
Thereby offloading developers and
empowering customers and consultants to
create tests in a more agile, quicker,
and cost-effective way.
And we have a number of sessions on this
tool already, both from when we launched
it, but also some follow-up sessions on
additional functionality. So, if this is
a new thing to you, I highly recommend
watching those sessions either before
you continue with this or after. And
we'll add some links in the description
on those sessions.
But in this release, we are now moving
the page scripting from preview into
making it generally available. And a big
part of getting there has been to sort
of finish it properly. So, it's now
fully localized. Every user-facing
string is translated, all steps, error
messages, tooltips, and any hard-coded
user-facing strings have been updated.
And on top of that, we made a pass on
accessibility and usability, as well as
some feedback on look and feel.
So, now it's ready for broad production
use across all languages. Beyond
finishing and the polishing, we actually
have added a few more capabilities in
the tool, so that the recordings can
capture more. First, we have support for
multiple selection in grids, so that you
can record selecting several rows in a
list and run bulk actions
to capture those and replay them again.
And secondly, you can now validate the
text shown in a message or in an error
dialogue to actually assess
when that happens.
And as you can see here
as an
example of actually validating an error
message.
And that turns the recording into
actually a real assertion, not just a
sequence of clicks.
So please go and use the tool to record
flows. I mean since we
launched it, it's now also possible to
actually use agents to try to generate
these scripts and and run them. So it's
a really good and powerful tool.
Thank you.